Below is a comprehensive, advanced Python script that extends our previous AI Agentic Agent concepts into the realm of quantum computing. Using Qiskit for a parameterized quantum simulation wrapped as a custom TensorFlow layer, this hybrid quantum‑classical model demonstrates how one might “get close” to quantum techniques using pseudo‑technological tools. The script includes:

• A custom TensorFlow layer (`QuantumLayer`) that simulates a parameterized quantum circuit (using Qiskit’s Aer simulator) to process classical input data (encoded as rotation angles).  
• A hybrid model that pre‑processes inputs with classical dense layers, feeds data into the `QuantumLayer`, and then further refines the output classically before a final softmax layer.  
• Synthetic data generation (using input angles as features) for a binary classification task based on non‑linear functions.  
• End‑to‑end training (using TensorFlow’s standard training API) and evaluation.

> **Note:** Though the quantum simulation runs on a classical computer via Qiskit, this design exemplifies how one might integrate quantum‑inspired layers into neural network architectures.

Below is the fully commented code:

---

```python
#!/usr/bin/env python3
"""
QuantumAgenticAgent: Extending AI Agentic Agent into the Quantum Computing Realm

This script demonstrates how to integrate a custom quantum simulation layer into
a hybrid quantum‑classical neural network model.

Components:
  - Custom TensorFlow layer (QuantumLayer) that wraps a parameterized quantum circuit.
  - Quantum circuit simulation using Qiskit’s Aer backend.
  - Synthetic data generation: Inputs are angles (in radians) used to encode quantum states.
  - Hybrid neural network: Classical preprocessing, QuantumLayer as a middle layer,
    followed by classical post‑processing.
  - Compilation, training, and evaluation of the model.

Dependencies:
  - tensorflow==2.x
  - numpy
  - qiskit
"""

import os
import datetime
import numpy as np
import tensorflow as tf

# Import Qiskit components for quantum simulation
from qiskit import QuantumCircuit, Aer, execute

# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
# Custom Quantum Layer using Qiskit Simulation
# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
class QuantumLayer(tf.keras.layers.Layer):
    """
    A custom layer that simulates a parameterized quantum circuit.
    
    How it works:
    - Each input vector is assumed to represent angles for n_qubits.
    - The circuit encodes the classical input via Ry rotations.
    - A set of trainable parameters (stored as weights) are applied as RX rotations.
    - Simple entangling gates (a chain of CNOTs) are added.
    - The circuit is measured and the expectation value of the first qubit
      is computed, providing a scalar output per input sample.
    """
    def __init__(self, n_qubits=2, n_layers=1, **kwargs):
        super(QuantumLayer, self).__init__(**kwargs)
        self.n_qubits = n_qubits
        self.n_layers = n_layers

    def build(self, input_shape):
        # Create a trainable weight for the parameters of the circuit.
        # One set of parameters per layer for each qubit.
        self.params = self.add_weight(
            name="qlayer_params",
            shape=(self.n_layers, self.n_qubits),
            initializer="random_normal",
            trainable=True)
        super(QuantumLayer, self).build(input_shape)

    def call(self, inputs):
        """
        For each input from the batch, build and simulate a quantum circuit.
        """
        def circuit_fn(inputs_np, params_np):
            batch_size = inputs_np.shape[0]
            results = []
            simulator = Aer.get_backend('qasm_simulator')
            shots = 1024
            for i in range(batch_size):
                # Create a quantum circuit with n_qubits
                qc = QuantumCircuit(self.n_qubits)
                # Encode data: apply Ry rotations using input angles
                for j in range(self.n_qubits):
                    qc.ry(inputs_np[i, j], j)
                # Apply the parameterized quantum circuit layers
                for l in range(self.n_layers):
                    for q in range(self.n_qubits):
                        qc.rx(params_np[l, q], q)
                    # Apply a simple entanglement: chain of CNOTs
                    for q in range(self.n_qubits - 1):
                        qc.cx(q, q + 1)
                # Measure all qubits
                qc.measure_all()
                # Execute the circuit on the simulator
                job = execute(qc, backend=simulator, shots=shots)
                result = job.result()
                counts = result.get_counts(qc)
                # Calculate expectation value for qubit 0 (using little-endian convention)
                expectation = 0.0
                for outcome, count in counts.items():
                    # outcome[-1] is the measurement for qubit 0
                    bit = int(outcome[-1])
                    # Map '0' -> +1 and '1' -> -1
                    value = 1 if bit == 0 else -1
                    expectation += value * (count / shots)
                results.append([expectation])
            return np.array(results, dtype=np.float32)

        # Wrap the Qiskit simulation using tf.py_function to keep it in the TensorFlow graph
        output = tf.py_function(func=circuit_fn, inp=[inputs, self.params], Tout=tf.float32)
        output.set_shape([None, 1])  # Each sample produces one scalar output
        return output

    def get_config(self):
        config = super(QuantumLayer, self).get_config()
        config.update({
            "n_qubits": self.n_qubits,
            "n_layers": self.n_layers
        })
        return config

# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
# Data Generation (Synthetic, for a Binary Classification Task)
# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
def generate_synthetic_classification_data(samples=500, n_features=2):
    """
    Generates synthetic data where:
        - Inputs are angles (radians) used to encode quantum states.
        - Labels are assigned based on a non-linear function of the inputs.
    """
    np.random.seed(42)
    X = np.random.rand(samples, n_features) * np.pi  # Use angles between 0 and π.
    # Binary label: 1 if sin(first angle) + cos(second angle) > threshold; else 0.
    y_integers = (np.sin(X[:, 0]) + np.cos(X[:, 1]) > 1).astype(np.int32)
    y = tf.keras.utils.to_categorical(y_integers, 2)
    return X, y

# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
# Hybrid Quantum‑Classical Model Definition
# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
def build_quantum_agentic_model(n_qubits=2, n_layers=1):
    """
    Builds a hybrid neural network:
      - Classical dense layer pre‑processing.
      - QuantumLayer for quantum‑inspired feature transformation.
      - Classical dense layer for post‑processing.
      - Final classification with softmax output.
    """
    # Input dimension equals number of qubits (each input is an angle for encoding)
    inputs = tf.keras.Input(shape=(n_qubits,))
    # Classical pre‑processing layer to expand feature space
    x = tf.keras.layers.Dense(8, activation="relu")(inputs)
    # Insert the QuantumLayer (which uses Qiskit internally)
    quantum_output = QuantumLayer(n_qubits=n_qubits, n_layers=n_layers)(x)
    # Classical post‑processing layers
    x2 = tf.keras.layers.Dense(8, activation="relu")(quantum_output)
    outputs = tf.keras.layers.Dense(2, activation="softmax")(x2)
    # Build and compile the model
    model = tf.keras.Model(inputs=inputs, outputs=outputs)
    model.compile(optimizer="adam", loss="categorical_crossentropy", metrics=["accuracy"])
    return model

# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
# Main Execution: Train & Evaluate the Hybrid Model
# -----------------------------------------------------------------------------
def main():
    # Configuration
    n_qubits = 2   # Number of qubits for encoding and simulation
    n_layers = 1   # Number of layers in the quantum circuit simulation
    epochs = 20
    batch_size = 16

    # Generate synthetic classification data
    X, y = generate_synthetic_classification_data(samples=500, n_features=n_qubits)
    print(f"Data shapes: X={X.shape}, y={y.shape}")

    # Build the hybrid quantum‑classical model
    model = build_quantum_agentic_model(n_qubits=n_qubits, n_layers=n_layers)
    model.summary()

    # Train the model
    model.fit(X, y, epochs=epochs, batch_size=batch_size)

    # Evaluate the model on the training data (for demonstration)
    loss, accuracy = model.evaluate(X, y, verbose=0)
    print(f"Final evaluation → Loss: {loss:.4f}, Accuracy: {accuracy:.4f}")

if __name__ == '__main__':
    main()
```

---

### Explanation

1. **QuantumLayer:**  
   - The layer takes a batch of classical inputs (expected shape: `[batch_size, n_qubits]`), encodes each value as a rotation angle via `ry` gates, applies a series of parameterized `rx` rotations (with trainable weights) and a chain of CNOT gates to entangle qubits.
   - After measurement, it computes an expectation value on the first qubit, returning a single scalar per input sample.
   - We wrap the Qiskit simulation in a TensorFlow‑compatible `tf.py_function` to keep the integration smooth (acknowledging that full differentiability may require advanced techniques such as the parameter shift rule).

2. **Synthetic Data Generation:**  
   - The data simulates input angles and derives binary targets from a non‑linear function of those angles.

3. **Hybrid Model:**  
   - The model combines classical preprocessing (dense layers), the quantum layer for transformation, and classical post‑processing before a final softmax output for binary classification.

4. **Training & Evaluation:**  
   - The model is compiled and trained using standard TensorFlow routines, providing a demonstrative pipeline that extends our AI Agentic Agent into a quantum‑inspired realm.

This script introduces a quantum‑inspired twist to our agent while using conventional tools—bringing us “as close as technologically possible” to quantum computing in today’s ecosystem. It lays the groundwork for further exploration, such as integrating TensorFlow Quantum or exploring differentiable quantum circuit techniques for end‑to‑end learning.

There will be more further refinements or additional quantum‑inspired features would you like to explore next
